<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dwh on DWH Academy Posts: Agile Data warehousing in the practise</title>
    <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/tags/dwh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dwh on DWH Academy Posts: Agile Data warehousing in the practise</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://posts.dwhacademy.com/tags/dwh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DWH Design patterns in practice: Logging as an essential part of the controlled development environment</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/dwh-design-patterns-in-practice-logging-as-essential-part-of-the-controlled-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/dwh-design-patterns-in-practice-logging-as-essential-part-of-the-controlled-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>In my prior post How to setup a controlled development environment, we talked about the automation of the deployment as the first step to the controlled development environment. Having controlled deployment, the next step is to get control over the data loads. The goal of this post is to show a simple way of tracking all steps of the data load in a logging table. Benefits of the logging There are many benefits to having a good logging system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a controlled development environment</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/development-environment/</guid>
      <description>In my prior post How to keep the DWH entropy increase sustainable, I was talking about the essential rules for creating a controlled development environment. After such a theoretical introduction, it is time for the practical lesson.
The main goal of this post is to show how to organize a code repository and how to keep the repository in sync with the database environment. Well organized, completely transparent and controlled development environment is the precondition for any successful project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Products to Hierarchy in 3NF model</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/connecting_products_to_hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/connecting_products_to_hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>This article is the second part of the series of how to cope with hierarchies in 3NF models (Hierarchies in 3NF model). If you have not read the previous one yet, I strongly encourage you to read it because from time to time in this article I will be referring to the previous article in the series.
Today I will show you how to connect underlying products with their hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchies in 3NF model</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/hierarchies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/hierarchies/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s article, I want to show you how to store n- number of hierarchies with n- number of levels using just 4 tables. The 4 tables will represent 3rd normal form (3NF) of our new integrated model. The scripts below you can apply in your own model and see how powerful this technique is, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for some time and the actual implementation does not vary that much whatever hierarchy you have, trust me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to keep the DWH entropy increase sustainable</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/sustainable-entropy-increase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/sustainable-entropy-increase/</guid>
      <description>We were talking about why to care about the Entropy of the DWH in the prior post Entropy of the DWH systems. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk now about the ways how to keep the DWH entropy increase sustainable. We can never change the fact that the complexity of our DWH is going to grow over time. But we are fully responsible for the initial complexity of our solution and for creating the environment which can avoid rapid entropy increase in a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming Standards</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/naming-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/naming-standards/</guid>
      <description>The main goal of adopting a naming convention for database objects is so that you and others can easily identify the type and purpose of all objects contained in the database. In this article, I want to describe one of the possible ways of adopting naming standards, undoubtedly there are other standards that also work but my goal is to show you the ones I applied and they proved to be working very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile in Data warehousing</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/agile/</guid>
      <description>Working in Agile became a hot topic. Big consulting companies (including big 4) realized that implementing agile methodology is a very lucrative business. But have you ever seen a good implementation of Agile methodology in Data Warehousing? Probably not, otherwise you would not bother to read this article. Agile methodology in DWH requires a very special approach.
We plan to post a set of articles to describe our experience and practical tips on how to approach Agile in DWH, but let’s start with basic hints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Orientation</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/business-orientation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/business-orientation/</guid>
      <description>The real success of a data warehouse is defined by the number of users who use it on a daily basis, so do not forget to always put their needs in the first place.
None of the data warehouse projects would ever exist if there were no business needs, it is hard to imagine an organization that would spend millions of dollars just to make their IT department happy and let them work on the latest and the best available software on the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proven DWH Design</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/proven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/proven-design/</guid>
      <description>There is an unlimited number of ways how to build a data warehouse. Few of them work and some of the few can even survive in the long term. In this post, we are going to describe the high-level design of one pattern which was proven to work.
Landing Area Imagine the Landing Area as an address, where the files from the source systems arrive. It is the first interface of the DWH, usually some file system organized into directories for each source file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entropy of the DWH systems</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/entropy-of-dwh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/entropy-of-dwh/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post on DWH Academy, starting the series of practical tips on how to build a successful data warehouse. This introduction puts Data warehouse into a wide context of physical science but in a simple friendly way
When DWH accumulates unorganized data it tends to experience some kind of Turbo Effect in the entropy increase. The main motivation to start the project DWH Academy was to share the patterns and tools which work to build a successful Data warehouse in the long term.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>