<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on DWH Academy Posts</title>
    <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on DWH Academy Posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://posts.dwhacademy.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchies in 3NF model</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/hierarchies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/hierarchies/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s article, I want to show you how to store n- number of hierarchies with n- number of levels using just 4 tables. The 4 tables will represent 3rd normal form (3NF) of our new integrated model. The scripts below you can apply in your own model and see how powerful this technique is, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for some time and the actual implementation does not vary that much whatever hierarchy you have, trust me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to keep the DWH entropy increase sustainable</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/sustainable-entropy-increase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/sustainable-entropy-increase/</guid>
      <description>We were talking about why to care about the Entropy of the DWH in the prior post Entropy of the DWH systems. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk now about the ways how to keep the DWH entropy increase sustainable. We can never change the fact that the complexity of our DWH is going to grow over time. But we are fully responsible for the initial complexity of our solution and for creating the environment which can avoid rapid entropy increase in a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming Standards</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/naming-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/naming-standards/</guid>
      <description>The main goal of adopting a naming convention for database objects is so that you and others can easily identify the type and purpose of all objects contained in the database. In this article, I want to describe one of the possible ways of adopting naming standards, undoubtedly there are other standards that also work but my goal is to show you the ones I applied and they proved to be working very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proven DWH Design</title>
      <link>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/proven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://posts.dwhacademy.com/proven-design/</guid>
      <description>There is an unlimited number of ways how to build a data warehouse. Few of them work and some of the few can even survive in the long term. In this post, we are going to describe the high-level design of one pattern which was proven to work.
Landing Area Imagine the Landing Area as an address, where the files from the source systems arrive. It is the first interface of the DWH, usually some file system organized into directories for each source file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>